An official website of the United States government

Here’s how you know

Here's how you know

**The .gov means it’s official.**  
Federal government websites often end in .gov or .mil. Before sharing sensitive information, make sure you’re on a federal government site.

**The site is secure.**  
The **https://** ensures that you are connecting to the official website and that any information you provide is encrypted and transmitted securely.

Translation Menu
----------------

Secondary Menu
--------------

_[](https://www.ftc.gov/ "Home")_

Menu

Main Menu Mega
--------------

* Show/hide Enforcement menu items
    
    ----------------------------------------------
    
    We enforce federal competition and consumer protection laws that prevent anticompetitive, deceptive, and unfair business practices.

    ### Search or browse  
    the Legal Library
    
    Find legal resources and guidance to understand your business responsibilities and comply with the law.

    Search small Search
    
    Sections
    --------

    Take action
    -----------

    Competition Matters Blog
    ------------------------
    
    Competition Matters
    
    ### [Slow the Roll-up: Help Shine a Light on Serial Acquisitions](https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement/competition-matters/2024/05/slow-roll-help-shine-light-serial-acquisitions)
    
    Henry Liu, Director of the Bureau of Competition
    
    May 23, 2024

* Show/hide Policy menu items
    
    ------------------------------------
    
    We work to advance government policies that protect consumers and promote competition.

    ### Search or browse  
    the Legal Library
    
    Find legal resources and guidance to understand your business responsibilities and comply with the law.

    Search small Search
    
    Sections
    --------

    Take action
    -----------

    Feature
    -------

    ### Vision and Priorities
    
    Memo from Chair Lina M. Khan to commission staff and commissioners regarding the vision and priorities for the FTC.

    Technology Blog
    ---------------
    
    Technology Blog
    
    ### [Avoiding Outages and Preventing Widespread System Failures](https://www.ftc.gov/policy/advocacy-research/tech-at-ftc/2024/08/avoiding-outages-preventing-widespread-system-failures)
    
    Staff at the FTC
    
    August 13, 2024

* Show/hide Advice and Guidance menu items
    
    Advice and Guidance
    -------------------
    
    Learn more about your rights as a consumer and how to spot and avoid scams. Find the resources you need to understand how consumer protection law impacts your business.
    
    Take action
    -----------

    ------------------------------------------------

    ----------------------------------------------------------

    ### Servicemembers:  
    Your tool for financial readiness

    ### Get consumer protection basics, plain and simple

    ### Learn how the FTC protects free enterprise and consumers

    ### Looking for competition guidance?

* Show/hide News and Events menu items
    
    --------------------------------------------------
    
    Latest News
    -----------

    ### [FTC Sends More Than $17 Million to Consumers Harmed by Brigit’s Deceptive Claims, Junk Fees, and Confusing Cancellation Process](https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2024/11/ftc-sends-more-17-million-consumers-harmed-brigits-deceptive-claims-junk-fees-confusing-cancellation)
    
    November 4, 2024

    Upcoming Event
    --------------
    
    Nov07
    
    ### [Ex Parte Meeting on Unfair or Deceptive Fees Rulemaking between Commissioner Ferguson's Office and the Travel Management Coalition](https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/events/2024/11/ex-parte-meeting-unfair-or-deceptive-fees-rulemaking-between-commissioner-fergusons-office-travel)
    
    Thursday, November 7, 2024 | 10:30AM

    Sections
    --------

    Follow us on social media
    -------------------------

    Feature
    -------

    ### [Noncompete Rule: What You Should Know](https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/features/noncompetes "Noncompete Rule Feature")
    
    Visit the Noncompetes feature page for more information, including factsheets featuring stories on how the rule can benefit Americans.
    
    Latest Data Visualization
    -------------------------

    ### [FTC Refunds to Consumers](https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/federal.trade.commission/viz/Refunds_15797958402020/RefundsbyCase)
    
    Explore refund statistics including where refunds were sent and the dollar amounts refunded with this visualization.
    
* Show/hide About the FTC menu items
    
    ----------------------------------------------
    
    Our mission is protecting the public from deceptive or unfair business practices and from unfair methods of competition through law enforcement, advocacy, research, and education.

    Sections
    --------

    Featured
    --------

    ### Meet the Chair
    
    Lina M. Khan was sworn in as Chair of the Federal Trade Commission on June 15, 2021.

* [Search](https://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=ftc_prod) Show/hide Search menu items
    
     Enter Search Term(s):   
    
    Looking for legal documents or records? Search the [Legal Library](https://www.ftc.gov/legal-library) instead.

Translation Menu
----------------

Secondary Menu
--------------

* [Enforcement](https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement) Show/hide Enforcement menu items
* [Policy](https://www.ftc.gov/policy) Show/hide Policy menu items
* Advice and Guidance Show/hide Advice and Guidance menu items
* [News and Events](https://www.ftc.gov/news-events) Show/hide News and Events menu items
* [About the FTC](https://www.ftc.gov/about-ftc) Show/hide About the FTC menu items

 Enter Search Term(s):   

Looking for legal documents or records? Search the [Legal Library](https://www.ftc.gov/legal-library) instead.

Privacy Policy
==============

Breadcrumb
----------

1. [Home](https://www.ftc.gov/)
2. [Policy and Notices](https://www.ftc.gov/policy-notices)

Policy and Notices Menu
-----------------------

--------------------------------------------------------

* [Notification and Federal Employee Antidiscrimination and Retaliation Act (No FEAR) P.L. 107-174](https://www.ftc.gov/policy-notices/no-fear-act)

What Does the FTC Do with Your Personal Information?
----------------------------------------------------

### Our Privacy Policy

Federal law requires us to tell you how we collect, use, share, and protect your personal information. Federal law also limits how we can use your personal information. Protecting the privacy and security of consumers' personal information is very important to us. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do with the personal information we collect both online and offline.

When you contact us to help you with a problem, we may collect personal information about you. We collect and use only the information necessary to respond to your concerns and conduct investigations. In most instances, we collect minimal personal information, such as name, address, telephone number, or email address. In limited cases, depending on the nature of your request or of our law enforcement investigations, we also may collect other personal information such as Social Security numbers, account numbers, or mortgage or health information. We also may collect information about your visit to our websites for security and internal operations purposes.

When do we collect personal information?
----------------------------------------

### When you contact us...

* to order publications, obtain redress, or register for the National Do Not Call Registry.
* to report fraud or identity theft.
* to file a public comment or participate in a rulemaking, workshop, or community engagement project.

### When we contact you...

* to ask if you will participate in a consumer survey.
* to provide information in response to a subpoena or other legal process.

### When we contact others...

* to collect information about potential victims when we investigate possible law violations.

Where does your information go?
-------------------------------

### Within the FTC...

* we use consumer information to further our law enforcement investigations.
* our contractors use your information when they perform certain services, such as operating the National Do Not Call Registry or our Consumer Response Center, processing redress claims, or fulfilling your order for publications.

### To other government agencies (federal, state, local, international)...

* we work with our partners to investigate complaints, coordinate law enforcement investigations, cooperate with oversight investigations, or follow up on ID theft reports.

### To others outside government...

* we post public comments and transcripts, including names, state of residence, and other non-confidential information, on the FTC website in a rulemaking, workshop, blog, or other public FTC proceeding.
* we provide information to credit bureaus for complaints about consumer fraud, ID theft, or credit reports.
* we provide only your phone number to telemarketers to enforce the National Do Not Call Registry.
* we provide information to businesses or individuals in response to court orders, subpoenas, discovery requests, or Freedom of Information Act requests, or to resolve complaints.
* we use [third-party services](https://www.ftc.gov/faq/ftc-info/information-collected-third-party-services) on our websites to assist in communicating or interacting with the public.

Additional FTC Privacy-Related Information
------------------------------------------

Privacy Act Information
-----------------------

The FTC’s Privacy Act rules – including our procedures, timelines, and instructions for submitting Privacy Act requests, and a list of FTC systems of records that are exempt from the Act’s requirements –  are published at [16 C.F.R. 4.13](http://www.ecfr.gov/cgi-bin/text-idx?SID=04a711d6460cb5811b7b9acc0e359ead&mc=true&node=se16.1.4_113&rgn=div8).

* List of [FTC Privacy Act Systems of Records](https://www.ftc.gov/site-information/privacy-policy/privacy-act-systems)
* Seeking non-public FTC records?  [Make a FOIA Request](https://www.ftc.gov/about-ftc/foia/make-foia-request).
* Seeking non-public FTC records about you or your dependent? [Submit a Privacy Act Request](https://www.ftc.gov/site-information/privacy-policy/privacy-act-request)

Questions or Complaints About This Privacy Policy
-------------------------------------------------

Write to the FTC's Chief Privacy Officer:

John Krebs

Federal Trade Commission  
600 Pennsylvania Ave., NW, H-350  
Washington, DC 20580  

Questions About Identity Theft & Online Issues
----------------------------------------------

Visit [ftc.gov/idtheft](https://www.ftc.gov/idtheft) to learn about the crime of identity theft, including detailed information to help you deter, detect, and defend against it.

Visit [OnGuardOnline](https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/features/feature-0038-onguardonline) to learn how to be on guard against Internet fraud, secure your computer, and protect your personal information.

Questions About Other Issues
----------------------------

Visit our [Contact Us](https://www.ftc.gov/contact) page to find email, phone, and mail contact information and links to our secure online complaint forms.

Frequently Asked Questions
--------------------------

Find answers to common questions about FTC.gov and its privacy, data collection and data sharing policies from our [Privacy Policy FAQs](https://www.ftc.gov/site-information/privacy-policy/frequently-asked-questions).

Last Updated: March 2023

_[](https://www.ftc.gov/ "Home")_

Menu

Secondary Menu
--------------

Main navigation
---------------

* Advice and Guidance

Footer
------
